Finding Aid for the Marion H. Briggs Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Marion H. Briggs Collection
1883-1948
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0574
.21 linear feet
Biography
Marion H. Briggs, a native of Spencerville, Ohio, served in the U. S. Army during World War I. His overseas service was spent with the 147th U. S. Infantry Med. Dept. in Belgium, France, and Germany.
This collection was found and donated by Shanda Springer.
Scope and Contents
This .21 linear feet collection of 28 items contains 18 pieces of correspondence written to family members primarily during World War I pertaining to army life and health. The collection also contains a booklet, map, pamphlet, and roster from the late 19th century. The collection is arranged in 14 file folders.
- Correspondence
  - handwritten postal card, August 4, 1886
  - handwritten letter, October 24, 1917
  - handwritten letter w/envelope, November 5, 1917
  - handwritten letter w/envelope, November 26, 1917
  - handwritten letter, February 27, 1918
  - handwritten letter w/envelope, April 6, 1918
  - handwritten letter w/envelope, August 18, 1918
  - handwritten letter w/envelope, October 5, 1918
  - handwritten letter w/envelope, October 12, 1918
  - handwritten letter w/envelope, October 13, 1918
  - handwritten letter w/envelope, November 3, 1918
  - handwritten letter, November 15, 1918
  - handwritten Christmas card w/envelope, November 25, 1918
  - handwritten letter, November 26, 1918
  - handwritten letter w/envelope, January 19, 1919
  - handwritten letter, August 1920
  - handwritten postal card, January 1924
  - birthday card w/envelope, July 1946
- Booklet
  - The Young Voyagers, by Oliver Optic, 1883
- Map w/descriptions
  - Chickamauga: A Famous Battlefield Issued by Passenger Traffic Department - Queen & Crescent Route
- Pamphlet
  - Rules and Regulations – Grand Army of the Republic, 1883
- Photographs
  - Spencerville, Ohio, April 8, 1948 – (3)
- Poem
  - handwritten in pencil – not titled Telegram paper of Erie Railroad Company, July 14, 1906
  - Undated – handwritten in pencil – not titled
- Roster
  - Ohio Veterans Association of Northern Indiana, 1886
- Stationery
  - Blank – embossed w/Eagle – (2)